残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
神話になれ
In emergencies, it can switch to a built-in battery with an active life of one minute at full power and no more than five minutes in the minimal activity gain mode.
This is due to our current limit in battery capacity technology. Do you understand?
Yes.
Now let's continue from where we left off yesterday. Initiate induction mode.
Position the target in the center, then squeeze the trigger switch on.
Take it easy. Position the target in the center.
Roll the switch.
Next.
You know, I can't help but wonder why Shinji agreed to pilot again.
It seems that he simply does what he's told to do. I suppose that's just his way of getting through life.
This attack okay.
Position target in the center and pull the switch.
Position target in the center
POSITION TARGET IN THE CENTER
Miss Misato, it's morning already
I just got back from night duty a little while ago
I don't have to go to work until this evening
so please let me sleep
Okay, I'll go
Hey, is this okay Thursday?
It's burnable trash day
Take it to the garbage please
Okay
So how's school?
Oh, it's okay
Okay, see you
I'll see you later
Yes, hello?
Oh, it's you, Itsuko
How's it going? Are you getting along with him?
Him? Oh, Shinji
Well, it's been two weeks since he started school
And he doesn't seem to have changed
No one ever calls him
Calls him where?
Well, since I figured he'd be needing one
I gave him a cellular phone
I don't think he's ever used it though
Or received any calls
I'm not sure
But I don't think he has any friends
Well, I would guess that Shinji isn't exactly the sort of person who makes friends easily
Mm-hmm
Do you know the fable, The Hedgehog's Dilemma?
Hedgehog?
You mean those animals with the spiny hair?
Even though a hedgehog may want to become close with another hedgehog
The closer they get, the more they injure each other with their spines
Hmm
It's the same with some humans
The reason he seems so withdrawn is because he's afraid of being hurt
Well, he's just going to have to learn
Someday
That part of growing up means
Finding a way to interact with others
While distancing pain
What's up, class rep?
Did you deliver the printout I gave you yesterday?
What?
Um, well, um, um
Well, um, there wasn't anybody home over at Toji's place
Mr. Ida, aren't you Suzuhara's friend?
Aren't you even just a little bit worried about him?
You don't suppose he was injured, do you?
What? You mean in that robot incident?
The television reports all said that nobody was injured
No way!
You saw where the explosion on Mount Takanosu was, didn't you?
There were fighters scrambled from a room in Komatsu
And there were troops from Isawa and Kyushu
I'll bet at least 10 or 20 people were injured
And there had to be a few fatalities, too
Toji!
Susuhara!
Where is everyone?
Has our entire class disappeared or what?
They've all either evacuated or they've transferred to other schools
No one wants to stay here after that last battle inside the city
Yeah, you're probably the only one who's actually enjoying the chance to see a real war
That's true!
And speaking of which, where have you been, Toji?
Why were you absent so long?
Did you get involved in the war?
No, but my little sister did
Ah!
She was crushed under a pile of debris
She survived, but she's been in the hospital ever since
Both my dad and granddad are working at the lab
And there's no way they can leave their posts
So, if I'm not with her, she's all alone
That robot's pilot was really dumb!
It made me so angry!
How could he wreck our own city?
What did that stupid idiot think he was doing?
Speaking of the pilot, have you heard the rumor about the transfer student?
What transfer student?
Him, over there!
He transferred in while you were absent
Right after the giant robot incident
Don't you think that's a little bit of an odd coincidence?
Shut up! He's coming!
All rise!
And so, humankind was about to face its greatest trial
In the last year of the 20th century
The massive meteor from outer space
Slammed into the continent of Antarctica
The continent's ice cap was melted almost instantaneously
The water level of the oceans increased dramatically
The Earth was thrown off its axis
And new devastatingly abnormal weather patterns were spawned
The lives of all living things on the planet were threatened
Several thousand species of flora and fauna
And half of the world's human population
Were lost in the immediate aftermath of the disaster
That was the so-called second impact
The survivors still had to live through the hell of worldwide economic collapse
Ethnic conflicts and civil wars
However, it has been 15 years since then
And in only 15 years we have restored ourselves
This is certainly proof of the human race's resilience
But even more so
It is the fruit of the blood, sweat and tears
Your father and mothers have dedicated to this cause
I lived and never found
Hey, sit down, you guys! We're still in class, you know!
Sit down now!
You're always so...
Now cut that out!
Do you think I can get anywhere?
Well, you know...
Hey, how did you get chosen?
Did you have to take a test?
Weren't you really scared?
What's a cockpit look like?
I'm not supposed to talk about classified stuff like that
Hey, what's the name of that robot?
I don't know much, but everyone calls it Ava or Unit 1
Ava?
What's its ultimate attack mode?
Some kind of vibrating knife
An ultrasonic wave
That's amazing! We are so proud of you!
And thus...
Oh...
That's all for the day
Ikari, where do you live?
In the outer part of the city?
Everybody stand up!
Belle!
Hey, you guys, can't you at least show some manners?
Sorry, newcomer, but I had to clobber you
I had to pop you one to work off my own anger
He's mean, huh?
His little sister was injured the last time you and your robot fought a battle
Well, that's his excuse anyway
I didn't have a choice
They made me pilot the stupid thing
Uh uh
Uh...
Ghhhhh
Huh?
There's an emergency. I'll report in first.
A special state of emergency has been declared for the Kanto and Chuga regions surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their designated shelters immediately.
Our cameras have sighted the target. It's penetrated our territorial waters.
Assume battle stations. Level one.
Roger. Prepare for anti-aircraft interception.
Tokyo-3, transforming to battle formation.
Initiate accommodation of the central block.
Jumping out, you Oyster on theannie.
Weót.
nezATOR CT.
Accommodation of the central block in the first through seven districts has been completed.
Notification of the government and other related ministries completed.
Present effective rate of anti-aircraft interception, 48 percent.
Status of civilians and non-combatants?
We've received reports that civilian evacuation has been completed.
Attention elementary school and junior high school students.
Please form groups with your individual classes.
Not again! Just text messages again?
It's no censorship. The government won't let them show any of the battle to us civilians.
Even though it's an incredible historic event.
The fourth angel would show up while Commander Ikari is away.
It's a lot sooner than we expected.
The last time they gave us 15 years.
This time around the break's only been three weeks.
They never care about our situation, do they?
They're the kind we women hate the most.
It's a waste of the taxpayers' money.
The committee is demanding that we dispatch an Evangelion again.
They're more obnoxious than the aliens. I'd have mobilized even if they hadn't asked.
Entry procedure initiated.
LCL oxygenated. Releasing airlock.
Hey, I need to talk to you privately for a second.
I want four.
Come on, please.
Oh, all right.
Hey, class rep!
Now what?
We've both gotta go to the bathroom.
You were supposed to do that before you came here.
So what's this all about?
I've gotta see it at least once in my life.
You mean the battle up there?
Nobody knows when the enemy will come the next time.
Kensuke, are you serious?
If we let this opportunity escape us, we may lose it forever.
Please, help me unlock the gate.
But you can get killed if you go out there.
If we stay here in the shelter, who's to say that the risk isn't the same?
If I might be killed anyway, I'd rather see it first.
You idiot. What do you think Nerve's for?
And what is Nerve's most important weapon?
It's the robot that new kid pilots.
He protected us the other day, but you hit him pretty hard.
Twice.
If he refuses to fight, we're all going to die.
Doesn't that make it your obligation to watch him fight?
Okay, you're not leaving me any options.
You'll do just about anything to get what you want, won't you?
Shinji, are you ready?
First, neutralize the enemy's AT field, then fire a volley.
Do it just like we practiced.
Can you handle that?
Launch, Ava!
Cool! All my efforts really paid off!
I've been waiting for this moment all my life!
Whoa!
There it is!
The AT field has been unfolded.
Do it just like we planned, okay, Shinji?
Okay!
Idiot!
You hit the enemy with your own smoke!
I don't believe it!
He's losing already!
It's not a problem.
I'm sending you a spare rifle!
Take it!
Shiji!
Geez!
Being beaten up must have really messed him up!
Oh, shut up!
Shut up!
Help!
The umbilical cable's been snapped off!
Ava has switched to its internal battery power source!
Four minutes, fifty-three seconds of activation remaining!
Haj classical
cold scream
The umbilical cable's been snapped off!
Eva has switched to its internal battery power source!
Four minutes, fifty-three seconds of activation remaining!
Thank you, all right?
pieces of activation
get that secure pallet to recover a salvage
of timing!
Shinji! Are you all right?
Shinji! Damage report!
No problem, Detective! He can make it!
Those are Shinji's classmates!
What are they doing there?
Why isn't he fighting back?
Maybe he can't move because we're down here!
He can't because of us!
Activation time remaining 3 minutes, 28 seconds!
Shinji! Let him into the cockpit!
Once you've got them, make a temporary retreat! We'll start again later!
What makes you think that unauthorized civilians can be allowed into the entry plug?
I'm authorizing it!
You're exceeding your authority, Captain!
Unit 1's remaining activation time, 3 minutes!
Shinji! Hold Ava on your current commands and inject the entry plug!
Hurry up and do it!
You two! Get in! Now!
What the?
This work!
My camera! My camera!
Abnormal conditions occurring in the nervous system!
Course! You've allowed two foreign bodies into the Matrix!
They're noise in the nerve impulse system!
Retreat! Get out of there!
Utilize recovery route 34! Retreat to the east side of the map!
Hey, Nukin! She said retreat! Nukin!
I mustn't run away!
The Progressive Knight's been engaged!
Obey my order, Shinji!
You've got to retreat!
Shinji!
That idiot!
Idiot!
Unit 1, activation time remaining 30 seconds!
AVA Unit 1, activationaround ceased!
The target is completely silent!
it's been
three days you mean since we were chewed out no since he stopped coming to school who is he
the new kid who else would i mean i wonder what he's been doing since then are you worried about
him no not exactly worried toji for someone who's so blunt and tactless you're pretty stubborn
if you had apologized to him back then you wouldn't have had to agonize over it for three days
here this is the new kid's phone number take it if you're so worried why don't you call it
so
fly me to the moon
and let me play
among the stars
let me see why
so
do
the
You are all alone, for all I worship at all.
Another one, please be true.
Another one, I love you.
Overwhelmed and unable to cope with his weakness, Shinji attempts to run away.
Quickly retrieved by the organization, he finds himself surrounded by unsympathetic ears.
And the only overtures of friendship come from his two classmates.
It happens in the next episode, where I'll be doling out another helping of fan service.